Kate Hevner Mueller papers, 1909-1981 C170
Indiana University Archives
- Correspondence, 1909-1979
  - General Correspondence, 1909-1979
    - Rose, Virginia -Classmate from Wilson College, 1955-1970 (Box 5)
    - Salisbury, Janet -University of Minnesota Press, 1953-1957 (Box 5)
    - Schleman, Helen -Dean of Women, Purdue University, 1953-1963 (Box 5)
    - Schuessler, Karl, 1966; 1974 (Box 5)
    - Scott, Nancy E. -Former teacher from Wilson College, 1952-1959 (Box 5)
    - Seashore, Robert, 1932-1938 (Box 5)
    - Seward, Doris, 1953-1957 (Box 5)
    - Shollenberger, Edith Dell -Sister of KHM (sometimes written as "Edith Delle" and "Edithdelle"), 1933-1971 (Box 5)
    - Shollenberger, Flossie -KHM's nephew Lew's wife, 1956-1977 (Box 5)
    - Skinner, B. F., "Fred", 1951; 1953 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Kerry -with Association for Higher Education (AHE), 1963-1968 (Box 5)
    - Stahr, Elvis -President of Indiana University, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
    - Stogdill, Hazel -Housekeeper for the Muellers, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Strang, Ruth -NAWDC, 1944-1968 (Box 5)
    - Strickland, Ruth, 1951-1976 (Box 5)
    - Sward, Keith, 1932-1933 (Box 5)
    - Swartz, Ruth, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Szorenyi, Emmi, 1948-1976 (Box 5)
    - Tangerman, Margaretta -Dean of Women, Department of Social Work and Sociology Valparaiso University, 1951-1969 (Box 5)
    - Taylor, Emily -Dean of Women, University of Kansas; Miami U, Oxford,Ohio, 1958-1965 (Box 5)
    - Thurstone, L.L. and Thelma, 1924-1965 (Box 5)
    - Tompkins, Pauline -with AAUW, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Vrenios (Kirkpatrick), Elizabeth, 1965-1974 (Box 5)
    - Ward-Steinman, David -San Diego State University Music Department, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Watson, Jack and Corrine, 1954-1976 (Box 5)
    - Weatherwax, Fannie, 1951-1965 (Box 5)
    - Wells, Herman B and Bernice (mother), 1949-1977 (Box 5)
    - White, Pauline, 1962 (Box 5)
    - Winther, Eric, 1966-1972 (Box 5)
    - Winther, Ingrid, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
    - Wright, Wendell "Whack" -Dean of the School of Education, 1938; 1955 (Box 5)
    - "Bonnie and Al (Pickett?)", 1961-1975 (Box 5)
    - "Cecil and Inez", 1958-1971 (Box 5)
    - "Eleanor", 1966; 1969 (Box 5)
    - "Evelyn and Otis", 1965-1972 (Box 5)
    - "Mary and Oscar", 1966 (Box 5)
    - "Miles and Clementine", 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    - "Orah", 1948-1957 (Box 5)
- Research Notes, 1920s-1970s
  - Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras: a history and analysis of their repertoires, seasons 1842-1843 through 1969-1970, undated
    - Financial Aid Application - Orchestra Project, undated (Box 5)
    - American Data, undated (Box 5)
      - "American, native, since 1890" -Data (Box 5)
      - "American, native and foreign born, before 1890" -Data (Box 5)
      - "American, 1950" -Data, notes, previous studies (Box 5)
      - "American Data Summaries 1950-1965" -Data (Box 5)
      - "American Data to 1970, Individual Composers by 5-year periods and charts, data" (Box 5)
      - "Americans, New Charts, 1973" (Box 5)
      - "APA Americans in Orchestras - September 1969" -Data and notes (Box 5)
    - Charts, undated (Box 5)
      - "Charts not used groups reclassified" (Box 5)
      - "Corrected Charts 1970" (Box 5)
      - "Individual Curves to 1950" (Box 5)
      - "Miscellaneous Charts and Pyramids to 1935" (Box 5)
      - "Progress Charts Informal (Steps, checks, reports)" (Box 5)
      - "Trial Charts to 1970" (Box 5)
      - "Various Charts" (Box 5)
    - City Data, undated (Box 5)
      - "Boston" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
      - "Boston, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Boston to 1950-1965, conductors" -notes (Box 5)
      - "Chicago" -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
      - "Chicago, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Chicago" - Data (Box 5)
      - "Cincinnati, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Cincinnati" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
      - "City Charts Seattle-Dallas to 1965, Individual Composers" (Box 5)
      - "City Data and Charts 1945-1949" (Box 5)
      - "Cleveland" -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
      - "Cleveland, Modern" - Data (Box 5)
      - "Cleveland" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Data Chart- Chicago, NY Phil., Philadelphia, Boston, Cleveland, St. Louis, Minneapolis, Cincinnati, LA, San Francisco" (Box 5)
      - "Indianapolis Data" (Box 5)
      - "Indianapolis Articles and Charts" (Box 5)
      - "Indianapolis Statistical Data" (Box 5)
      - "London Philharmonic" (Box 5)
      - "Los Angeles" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
      - "Minneapolis" -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
      - "Minneapolis, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Minneapolis" -Data (Box 5)
      - "New York Philharmonic, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "New York Philharmonic" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
      - "New York Philharmonic" (Box 5)
      - "New York Symphony" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
      - "New York Symphony" (Box 5)
      - "New York Symphony, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
      - "Philadelphia" -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
      - "Philadelphia, Modern"- data (Box 5)
      - "Philadelphia" -Data (Box 5)
      - "San Francisco" (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
          General
          (3 files)
      - "St. Louis" (Box 5)
        - -Data (Box 5)
        - -Data, 5 year periods (Box 5)
      - "St. Louis" (Box 5)
      - "St. Louis, Modern" -Data (Box 5)
    - Composers, undated (Box 5)
      - "Beethoven, Brahms, Sibelius, Wagner" -Data, drafts (Box 5)
      - "Composer Averages -All orchestras to 1965" (Box 5)
      - "Composer groups to 1950" (Box 5)
      - "Composers- individual orchestras to 1965" (Box 5)
      - "Composers, lists of unknowns and sources" (Box 5)
      - "Data, Summaries of Composers" (Box 5)
      - "Eminent Composers and Forgotten data to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "List of unknown composers" (Box 6)
      - "Individual Composers, Data by Orchestra to 1965 only" (Box 6)
      - "Major Composers, Master Copy 1965-1969" (Box 6)
      - "Moderns to 1950" -Data, manuscripts, clipping (Box 6)
      - "Modern, Foreign, to 1965 only" (Box 6)
      - "Schumann, Stravinsky" (Box 6)
      - "Tabulations of Younger Composers, Britten, Milhaud, etc." (Box 6)
    - Conductors, undated (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Charts -Boston to 1945" (Box 6)
      - "Conducting Charts, Chicago" (Box 6)
        (2 files)
      - "Chicago Conductors, Individual Composers to 1966" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Data, Griffith" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Charts - Kansas City" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Charts- New York Philharmonic (Individual composers and nationalities)" (Box 6)
      - "NY Philharmonic Conductor Periods 1898-1967" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Charts - New York Philharmonic to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Period Charts, Chicago, New York, Cleveland" (Box 6)
      - "City Conductor Period Charts to 1950" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Charts - other orchestras to 1950 only" (Box 6)
      - "Conductor Plotting Data" (Box 6)
    - Nationalities, undated (Box 6)
      - "Average National Groups, All Major Orchestras to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Charts for Various Orchestras, National groups to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Individuals, Nationalities, Charts to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "National Averages, Worksheets, Charts to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "National Groups by Orchestra to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Nationalities - British, Italian, Czech, to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Nationalities Charts to 1945" (Box 6)
      - "Nationalities Data to 1950, later to 1965" (Box 6)
      - "Nationality Final Data, Xerox Copies, corrected -Oct 1971" (Box 6)
    - Other Data, undated (Box 6)
      - "Computer Information" (Box 6)
      - "Piano Concertos" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Popularity Pyramid" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Program Sources 1967-1968" (Box 6)
      - "Programs, 1969-1970" -Programs, data, notes (Box 6)
      - "Progress Notes" (Box 6)
      - "Proofreaders Corrections" (Box 6)
      - "Timings, General Information, 1968" (Box 6)
      - "Various Drafts and Notes" (Box 6)
      - "Violin Concertos, Piano Concertos" -Data (Box 6)
    - Summaries/Drafts, undated (Box 6)
      - "Summaries of 15 Orchestras, 5 Year Periods, 1950-1965" (Box 6)
      - "Orchestra Summary" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Xerox Duplicates of Summaries and Samples of Cards, Etc. to 1965" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Xerox Summaries, All Orchestras 1950-1965" (Box 6)
      - "Summaries 1965-1969" (Box 6)
      - "Current Orchestra, Each Year Major Composers and Nationalities" (Box 6)
      - "Final Corrected Data for Orchestra History" -Data (Box 6)
      - "Abaco - R. Harris, Final" (Box 7)
      - "Hartman - Ribaupierre, Final" (Box 7)
      - "Rice - Zollner, Final" (Box 7)
      - "Minors A-H, Xerox of originals with corrections" (Box 7)
      - "Minors I-Z, Master Copy, Xerox of originals with corrections" (Box 7)
      - "A-H Minor and Major Originals for Final Typing" (Box 7)
      - "I-Z Minor and Major Originals for Final Typing" (Box 7)
  - General Research Notes, 1920-1979
    - Aesthetics (Box 7)
      - -notes, undated (Box 7)
      - - Study of form, color and design, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
      - Definitions -notes, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
      - Drawings, Experiental, ca. 1930s-1940s (Box 7)
      - "Teaching Literature Appreciation" Bibliographies -for class and research, ca. early 1930s (Box 7)
    - Aesthetic Appreciation Tests (not music), ca. late 1920s-early 1930s (Box 7)
    - Aesthetics Research, ca. 1929-1933 (Box 7)
    - Affective Psychology - Expressions, etc., ca. 1930s (Box 7)
    - Art (Box 7)
      - -Art survey data, 1937 (Box 7)
      - -Sample Pictures, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
      - -survey, notes, 1945 (Box 7)
    - Art Theory/Criticism -notes, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Art, Aesthetics -notes, ca. 1930s-1940s (Box 7)
    - Art Appreciation/Aesthetics (Box 7)
      - -Empathy, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
      - -Meier-Seashore reliability studies, ca. late 1920s (Box 7)
      - -materials for analysis, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
    - Art- Psychological/Philosophical Aspects, 1931; 1941 (Box 7)
    - Campus Morality Evaluation Forms, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Convocation Series- research for article, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Correlation Charts, instructions, ca. early 1930s (Box 7)
    - Editing done by KHM for other authors, undated (Box 7)
    - Educating Women for a Changing World, ca. 1954 (Box 7)
    - Factor Analysis, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 7)
    - German Women, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Hart, Philip- work on Symphony Repertoire project, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Humor -Psychological Aspects, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 7)
    - KHM's criticisms of John Mueller's writings, circa 1930s (Box 7)
    - Kinsey, Alfred, and the Institute for Sex research, Correspondence and News Clippings, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Literature (Box 7)
      - -Aesthetics -tests and notes, undated (Box 7)
      - -poetry report, ca. 1930s (Box 7)
    - Literature Aesthetics -Oregon Poetry Tests, Carroll tests, ca. 1931 (Box 7)
    - Marriage - College Age -notes, resources, ca. 1950; 1945 (Box 7)
    - Mental Health, for guidance and counselling, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Mental Test Theories - Thurstone (Box 7)
      - ca. 1925-1929 (Box 7)
      - 1925-1929 (Box 7)
    - Music (Box 7)
      - -graphs, undated (Box 7)
      - -Talent and training scales, ca. 1936 (Box 7)
    - Music Appreciation/Aesthetics (Box 7)
      - -Adjective Arrangements,charts evaluations, notes, ca. 1930s-1950s (Box 7)
      - -bibliography, Music Notation Test, charts, notes, ca. 1930s-1950s (Box 8)
      - -Mozart Minuet chart tracings, undated (Box 8)
      - -Oregon Music Discrimination Tests tests, keys, charts..., ca. 1930s (Box 8)
      - -Radio Talks, 1932 (Box 8)
      - -Seashore Music tests, etc., ca. 1930s (Box 8)
      - -study of violin/viola, undated (Box 8)
      - -tests, notes, undated (Box 8)
      - -tests, notes, charts, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box 8)
      - -test, teaching, ca. 1930s and later (Box 8)
    - Music Discrimination Test, ca. 1934 (Box 8)
    - Oregon Scale of Attitude Toward Music -Keys, tests, results, 1934 and later (Box 8)
    - Oregon Test for Appreciation toward Music -Revision by a student, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Performing Arts Administration, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Religion, late 1950s-early 1960s (Box 8)
    - Speech Notes (Box 8)
      - -Aesthetics of Art and Music Appreciation, 1938 (Box 8)
      - -Women's Education, ca 1950s (Box 8)
      - -Women's Employment, 1954-1959; 1969 (Box 8)
      - -Various quotes, examples, thoughts and drafts, undated (Box 8)
      - -Various themes and audiences, 1937-1944 (Box 8)
    - Occupations, Vocations -used with Guidance and Counselling, 1940s-1958 (Box 8)
    - Psychology of Sleep, ca. 1937 (Box 8)
    - Psychophysics -Thurstone, 1920-1937 (Box 8)
    - Student Activities -notes, ca. 1960s (Box 8)
    - Tracings for Musical Excerpts, ca. 1930s (Box 8)
      [Box 12]
    - Thesis - University of Chicago -notes, studies, drafts, 1927-1928 (Box 8)
    - Thurstone -Attitude Tests, ca. late 1920s- early 1930s (Box 8)
    - Thurstone Research Materials, 1950s-1953 (Box 8)
    - Various Notes, undated (Box 8)
    - Women (Box 8)
      - ca. 1930s-1970 (Box 8)
      - 1954-1964 (Box 8)
      - -Motivation, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 8)
- Teaching/Class Notes, 1920s-1970s
  - Subject, 1920-1970
    - Aesthetics, ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 8)
    - Applied Psychology -Exam Key, 1938 (Box 8)
    - Cheating, 1953-1965 (Box 8)
    - Critique of Student work by KHM and John Mueller, ca. 1949 (Box 8)
    - Critique by Student -Music/Poetry Discrimination using Oregon Test, undated (Box 8)
    - Discipline, 1952-1962 (Box 8)
    - Evaluation of University Services Materials, 1943-1947; 1970 (Box 8)
    - Faculty issues, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Finances at the University, 1954-1962 (Box 8)
    - Fraternities, 1956-1961 (Box 8)
    - Gradebook -unknown class, undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8)
    - Music Concepts, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
    - "Professional" chapter notes, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
    - Publications for Women Students, 1939; 1942; 1947 (Box 8)
    - Religious Issues, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
    - Romance/Dating, 1960-1963 (Box 8)
    - Student Activities, 1950-1967 (Box 8)
    - Women's Education, 1940s-1950s (Box 8)
  - Classes, 1930-1973
    - Psychology 72f (Minnesota) -Assignments, Exams, Records, 1930-1935 (Box 8)
    - Psychology 215f (Minnesota) -Bibliography, 1933 (Box 8)
    - Psychology 72s (Minnesota) -Syllabus, Final Exam, 1937 (Box 8)
    - Psychology 111a -Syllabus, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
    - P100 (Psychology) (Box 8)
      - -Data from students, 1952-1958 (Box 8)
      - -Experiments, 1951-1960 (Box 8)
      - -Handouts, Assignments, 1955-1961 (Box 8)
      - -Quizzes and Exams, 1961 (Box 8)
    - P490 (Problems in the Education of Women) -Handouts, Notes, Organization, 1955-1956 (Box 8)
    - G544 (Personnel, Guidance) (Box 8)
      - -Handouts, Final Exam, 1950s-1960s (Box 8)
      - -Handouts, mid 1960s (Box 8)
    - U546 ("College Personnel Work:Modern Theory and Current Problems") -Handouts, ca. 1960s (Box 8)
    - G546 (College Personnel Work) -Handouts, Syllabus, Assignments, Notes, ca. 1956 (Box 8)
    - C546 (Professional Training), ca. 1960s (Box 8)
    - G546 (College Personnel Work, Guidance) -Handouts, ca. 1960s (Box 8)
    - G784 (Guidance, Personnel) -Notes, Handouts, 1961-1973 (Box 8)
    - G784 (Seminar) -Handouts, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Student Work, 1930-1969 (Box 9)
    - C784 -Materials, Handouts, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    - G784 -Book Reviews by Students (alphabetical), Other Sources for Class with Notes, 1953-1965 (Box 9)
    - Student Assignments (Box 9)
      - dated, chronological order, 1930-1969 (Box 9)
      - undated, put in rough chronological order, 1930s-1960s (Box 9)
  - Professional Organizations, 1930s-1975
    - American Association of University Women, 1949-1967 (Box 9)
    - American Council on Education, 1947-1951 (Box 9)
    - American Personnel and Guidance Association/Ethics Committee, 1960-1966 (Box 9)
    - American Psychological Association Division 10: Aesthetics, 1952-1957 (Box 9)
    - Association for Higher Education, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
    - Carnegie Committee, University of Oregon, 1931 (Box 9)
    - Committees, Various, 1969; 1975 (Box 9)
    - "Conference on the Negro", 1968 (Box 9)
    - Counselling Survey, 1946 (Box 9)
    - Duties of the Dean of Women, ca. late 1930s-early 1940s (Box 9)
    - Germany Visits and Conferences, 1951 (Box 9)
    - International Council of Women Psychologists, 1957 (Box 9)
    - Lectures, Presentations, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Notes, Materials from Various conferences, ca. 1960s (Box 9)
    - Professional Services -Conferences, Evaluations, etc. with Schools; Surveys, ca. 1940s-1960s (Box 9)
    - Report of the Dean of Women, 1942-1943 (Box 9)
    - US Office of Education -Field Reader, 1960-1970 (Box 9)
    - Personnel Newsletters at Indiana, 1956-1959 (Box 9)
    - NAWDC Journal, Policies, Practices, 1959 (Box 9)
    - NAWDC Annual Journal Reports, ca. 1950s-1964 (Box 9)
    - National Association of Women's Deans and Counselors (NAWDC), 1949-1960 (Box 9)
    - NAWDC -Journal (Box 9)
      - 1962-1964 (Box 9)
      - 1965 (Box 9)
      - 1966 (Box 9)
      - 1967 (Box 9)
      - 1968 (Box 9)
      - 1969 (Box 9)
      - 1970-1975 (Box 9)
- Writings, 1928-1977
  - Speeches/Radio Broadcasts, undated
    - A 1970 Issue: Women (Box 9)
    - Contribution which Men Can Make to the Achievement of of Desirable Life Goals for Educated Women, 1954 (Box 9)
    - Audience Analysis, 1957 (Box 9)
    - The Complexities of Women, 1953 (Box 9)
    - The Educated Woman, 1954 (Box 9)
    - Educating Women for a Changing World -Mills College Commencement, 1963 (Box 9)
    - The Education of Women, 1952 (Box 9)
    - The Function of the Student Personnel Division on the 1963 Campus (Box 9)
    - Guidance for the Role of Women in Our Culture, 1950 (Box 9)
    - Higher Education as I See It, 1959 (Box 9)
    - How to Motivate Women to Want Desirable Life Goals After They Have Recognized Them, 1954 (Box 9)
    - Maturity, Apr 30, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Music Research, undated (Box 9)
    - NAWDAC Conference, 1956 (Box 9)
    - The Parable of the Talents and the Wise and Foolish Virgins, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Personnel Work, 1965 (Box 9)
    - The Problems and Education of Women, ca. 1950s (Box 9)
    - The Professional as an Individual, 1960 (Box 9)
    - The Scope of the Pressures and Opportunities that Face the Educated Woman, 1957 (Box 9)
    - A Seven-Decade View of Women's Lives, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Is Women's Education Relevant? -draft, final copy, 1969 (Box 9)
    - Women (Box 9)
      - 1954 (Box 9)
      - 1950s (Box 9)
      - -Various Drafts and for Different Audiences, 1947-1966 (Box 9)
      - Various Speeches -with Notes and Drafts, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Women's Education (Box 10)
      - 1960 (Box 10)
      - 1965 (Box 10)
    - A Psychological Test for Music Appreciation (Radio), Jul 13, 1932 (Box 10)
    - Good and Bad Music (Radio), Jul 20, 1932 (Box 10)
    - Working Women (Radio), ca. 1940 (Box 10)
    - Getting Along with People?, Apr 11, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Reviews, 1935-1973
    - American Women, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Beauty and Human Nature -Chandler, Albert Drafts and Letters, 1935 (Box 10)
    - The Brooklyn College Student: A Pilgrims Progress -Watson, Gladys Hipple, 1967 (Box 10)
    - College Peer Groups -Newcomb, Theodore M.; Wilson, Everett R., 1967 (Box 10)
    - Commission Report on Women for Women's Education, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Counseling and Discipline -Williamson, E.G., 1949 (Box 10)
    - Effects of Existing Mood and Order of Presentation of Vocal and Instrumental Music on Rated Mood Response to that Music -Eagle, Charles Thomas, Jr., 1973 (Box 10)
    - Reviews, Promotions, etc. Educating Women for a Changing World, 1954 (Box 10)
    - Experimental Research in the Psychology Music -Gordon, Edwin, 1972 (Box 10)
    - Go Spin You Jade -Hobman, D.L., 1958 (Box 10)
    - Handel's Messiah, A Touchstone of Taste -Myers, Robert Manson, 1948 (Box 10)
    - In Search of Beauty in Music -Seashore, 1948 (Box 10)
    - Musical Taste: Its Measurement and Cultural Nature -Farnsworth, Paul, 1951 (Box 10)
    - An Objective Psychology of Music -Lundin, Robert W. (Draft), 1954 (Box 10)
    - The Psychology of Discipline, undated (Box 10)
    - The Seven Ages of Woman -Parker, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Reviews, Advertisements for Student Personnel Work in Higher Education, 1961-1970 (Box 10)
    - You Must Relax -Jacobson, Edmund, undated (Box 10)
    - Reviews of Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras..., 1973 (Box 10)
  - Published Works, 1928-1977
    - Bibliography, ca. late 1930s (Box 10)
    - The Aesthetic Experience: A Psychological Description, 1937 (Box 10)
    - The Aesthetic Experience and Psychological Man, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Aesthetics Chapter XII, ca. 1930s (Box 10)
    - The Affective Character of the Major and Minor Modes in Music, 1935 (Box 10)
    - The Affective Value of Pitch and Tempo in Music, 1937 (Box 10)
    - American Music in the Symphonic Repertoire, 1969 (Box 10)
    - American Women and Their Work, 1964 (Box 10)
    - And Gladly Counsel, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Appreciation of Music and Test for the Appreciation of Music, 1934 (Box 10)
    - Art Appreciation - Oregon Proposal -Literature/Poetry Test, ca. 1930s (Box 10)
    - Class Structure and Academic and Social Success -with John Mueller, 1953 (Box 10)
    - A Comparative Study of Three Psychophysical Method (Thesis) -Thesis draft, editing, ca. 1928 (Box 10)
    - The Continuing Education of Women -Final copy, draft, ca. 1950s (Box 10)
    - Counselling Mature Women for Employment, March 1966 (Box 10)
    - Counselling for Mental Health, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Creativity, Art, and the Aesthetic Experience, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Criteria for Evaluation Professional Status, 1959 (Box 10)
    - The Cultural Pressures on Women, 1958-1968 (Box 10)
    - The Educated Woman, ca. 1954 (Box 10)
    - Education: Training Ground or Playground?, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Education of Women in the next 50 years -Chapter X, 1963; 1967 (Box 10)
    - Educational Issues and the Training of Student Personnel Workers, 1967 (Box 10)
    - The Effectiveness of Various Types of Art Appreciation Aids -With John Mueller, 1939 (Box 10)
    - An Empirical Study of Three Psychophysical Methods (Thesis) -With Thurstone's Comments, 1928 (Box 10)
    - An Experiment in Teaching Laboratory Psychology by the Project Method -with Mary Shirley, 1930 (Box 10)
    - Experimental Studies of the Elements of Expressions in Music, 1936 (Box 10)
    - An Experimental Study of the Affective Value of Sounds in Poetry, 1937 (Box 10)
    - Experimental Studies in the Affective Value of Colors and Lines, 1935 (Box 10)
    - Expression in Music: A Discussion of Experimental Studies and Theories, 1935 (Box 10)
    - Expressiveness in Music -Draft, 1949 (Box 10)
    - Guidance for the Role of Women in Our Culture, 1949 (Box 10)
    - A Graphic Matching Test for Properties of Frequency Distributions, 1931 (Box 10)
    - Higher Education :For the Individual Our Society Needs, 1959 (Box 10)
    - Indiana University's New Wartime Curricula for Women, 1942 (Box 10)
    - The Individual as a Professional Person, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Is Women's Education Relevant?, 1969 (Box 10)
    - Marriage, 1957 (Box 10)
    - Married Girls and Unmarried Mothers in the High Schools -with Florence Myers, 1965-1967 (Box 10)
    - The Marriage Trap, 1955 (Box 10)
    - The Married Student on the Campus -Final copy, drafts, notes, 1960 (Box 10)
    - A Method of Correcting for Guessing in True-False and Empirical Evidence in Support of It, 1932 (Box 10)
    - Motivating Young Women for Higher Education, 1958 (Box 10)
    - The Need for Commitment, 1964 (Box 10)